Guide to the Betty Bone Schiess papers, 1965-2014
Schiess, Betty Bone papers, 1965-2014
- Series VIII. Connie Cook Litigation Files
  - Civil intervention in church affairs (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Church/state - discrimination; aid to school (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Church/state - equal protection (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Church/state - general (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Church/state - religious sects (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Church/state - tax exemption (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - women and ordination - general (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Regularization/completion (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - McClure (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Serbian Church decision - hierarchy (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Validity - bishops (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Validity - church decisions and documents (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Validity - theologians (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Copies (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - 2. Betty Bone Schiess is a priest of the Episcopal Church (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - 3. Defendant diocese is a corporation (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - 4. Defendant diocese is engaged in interstate commerce and employs more than 15 people (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - 6. Defendant Cole acts as an employment agency (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - 7. Betty Bone Schiess was offered employment by Grace episcopal Church (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - 8. Defendant Cole refused to license Betty Bone Schiess because she's female (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - 9. Betty Bone Schiess Applied to Defendant Cole for employment in parishes where the Defendant acts as an employment agent (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - 10. Bishop Cole Admits that Betty Bone Schiess is qualified in all respects except sex (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - 11. The constitution/canon of the Episcopal Church do NOT prohibit women priests (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - 12. Defendant Cole needs no more authority to license Betty Bone Schiess (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - 14. Bishops conferred so as not to allow the women to function (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - 15. These meetings constituted a conspiracy (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - 16. The bishops prevented an ecclesiastical trial (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - 17. Defendant Cole prevented the filing of presentments against Betty Bone Schiess that might have produced an ecclesiastical trial (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - 18. These acts constitute a conspiracy (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - 19. Betty Bone Schiess filed a timely complaint with the New York State Human Rights Division (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - 20. Betty Bone Schiess filed a timely complaint with EEOC (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - 21. A notice of Betty Bone Schiess's right to sue was issued by EEOC (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - #1 client - research - separation of church and state (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - #1 client -research - women in religion (Box 13, Folder 45)
  - #1 client - CEC working papers (Box 13, Folder 46)
  - #1 client -expenditures and finances (Box 13, Folder 47-48)
  - #1 client - duplicates (Box 13, Folder 49)
  - #1 client - press clippings - 1974, relating to ordination of women and Schiess (Box 13, Folder 50)
  - #1 client - staff - working papers (duplicates) (Box 13, Folder 51)
  - #1 client - research - ordination validity (Box 13, Folder 52)
  - Answer (Box 13, Folder 53)
  - Northern District rules and info (Box 13, Folder 54)
  - Complaint drafts - old (Box 13, Folder 55)
  - #1 client (Box 13, Folder 56)
  - General convention, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 57)